<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Life on home</title>
    <link>https://tokisuno.github.io/blog/tags/life/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Life on home</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-ca</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 14:11:27 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://tokisuno.github.io/blog/tags/life/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Toki Talks - Personal Goals &amp; Gaming</title>
      <link>https://tokisuno.github.io/blog/posts/20250916/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 14:11:27 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tokisuno.github.io/blog/posts/20250916/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been a hard pill for me to swallow for some time now, but I think I have finally came to the realiziation that I don&amp;rsquo;t have as much time to game as I&amp;rsquo;d like to think I do. I also place way too much value on gaming achievements compared to other parts of my real life.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;real-life-goals-vs-gaming-goals&#34;&gt;Real life goals vs Gaming goals&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I made goals at the beginning of the year for myself, and looking back on them a lot of them had to do with gaming and other things that didn&amp;rsquo;t relate to my own personal growth. I do see gaming as some form of personal growth because I see competitive gaming as a form of personal expression. I&amp;rsquo;ve learned a lot about myself and how I deal with life through the lens of competitive gaming. But I have other things in my life that need more attention, like how I am going to live for the rest of my life and how I am going to make money doing things online. I sort of clock out at a certain point of the day (also depends heavily on how my health has been that day) and then spend the rest of the time gaming as a way of escapism. Although I have set real life goals for myself, I am scared of taking the next step forward in fear of rejection and thinking that what I do will never be good enough, and that I&amp;rsquo;ve wasted all my time and effort. I am familiar and comfortable with competitive gaming, so it&amp;rsquo;s easy to just hop over to. It&amp;rsquo;s the same with any other type of addiction or unhealthy relationship. We always go back to what&amp;rsquo;s familiar. In this case, it&amp;rsquo;s playing CS2.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Toki Talks - Throwaway</title>
      <link>https://tokisuno.github.io/blog/posts/20250911/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 11:43:05 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tokisuno.github.io/blog/posts/20250911/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Welcome back to another (late) weekly addition of Toki Talks!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;uneventful-week-honestly&#34;&gt;Uneventful week honestly&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is going to be more of a throw-away post as I don&amp;rsquo;t really have anything to really write about. I&amp;rsquo;ve spent a good portion of this week either gaming, editing, or resting. Yesterday especially was a pretty bad day for me so I spent a good portion just laying down in bed with fatigue and exhaustion. My mood also varies greatly and that&amp;rsquo;s due to the uncertainty of the future. I haven&amp;rsquo;t really programmed much lately and I feel like I&amp;rsquo;m falling behind on a lot of stuff. I also think that my newest video could have been done better but that&amp;rsquo;s neither here nor there. It just sorta sucks seeing everyone live their lives, and I&amp;rsquo;m just stuck with uncertainties with my health, unable to work.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Toki Talks - Becoming the person I want to be</title>
      <link>https://tokisuno.github.io/blog/posts/20250902/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 08:27:09 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tokisuno.github.io/blog/posts/20250902/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Welcome to this week of Toki Talks! This week, we&amp;rsquo;re going to get a little deeper into life.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;becoming-the-person-i-want-to-be&#34;&gt;Becoming the person I want to be&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve taken some time to think more about who I am, where I am, and how I want to get there. I&amp;rsquo;ve come to the realization that as I am right now &amp;ndash; although comfortable &amp;ndash; isn&amp;rsquo;t the same person I&amp;rsquo;d want to be in even a year, or two years at that. I don&amp;rsquo;t know if many of you have come to this realization, but it&amp;rsquo;s like experiencing another ego death where I feel like everything is becoming clearer and my life is being put back into perspective for me.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Toki Talks - I abandoned AwesomeWM...</title>
      <link>https://tokisuno.github.io/blog/posts/20250826/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 09:32:52 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tokisuno.github.io/blog/posts/20250826/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Welcome to this week&amp;rsquo;s installment of Toki Talks! I know that my video last week was supposed to cement/solidify that I am all about stability and simplicity instead of experimentation. With that being said, I left AwesomeWM.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;why-i-left-awesomewm&#34;&gt;Why I left AwesomeWM&amp;hellip;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To be quite honest, Awesome is much more than &amp;ldquo;just a window manager&amp;rdquo;. It&amp;rsquo;s a way of life. I mean this in the sense that the whole window manager feels less like a window manager and more like a customization framework. That&amp;rsquo;s cool and all, but it&amp;rsquo;s done in Lua, and the way that it&amp;rsquo;s implemented is probably really nice if you LIKE writing in Lua, and REALLY want to have total control over your environment. I used Awesome as a better OOTB DWM experience, and I can safely say that it does a good job of doing that.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Toki Talks - Obscure YouTubers I Remember</title>
      <link>https://tokisuno.github.io/blog/posts/20250819/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 08:31:28 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tokisuno.github.io/blog/posts/20250819/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;welcome&#34;&gt;Welcome!&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Welcome back to another week of Toki Talks! This week, I just want to shout out some old usernames of people I used to know/watch as a child. I hope that this page can be indexed online one day and I can either get in contact with some of lesser-known guys from my childhood, or maybe talk to some people who also watched these growing up :) &lt;em&gt;This isn&amp;rsquo;t an extensive list by any means, as I know there are a lot of people from art communities I used to be a part of that were either exposed, have changed names, have changed genders, and don&amp;rsquo;t want to be mentioned most likely to put their name to rest.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Toki Talks - Distracted by novel ideas</title>
      <link>https://tokisuno.github.io/blog/posts/20250814/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 11:14:45 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tokisuno.github.io/blog/posts/20250814/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Welcome once again to a late iteration of Toki Talks!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;i-really-like-things-i-dont-understand&#34;&gt;I really like things I don&amp;rsquo;t understand&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I think a lot of people with ADHD can relate to this, but I really like diving into what is novel and interesting to me. If I don&amp;rsquo;t understand, I want to understand it. Even at a surface level, if I cannot make sense of it in my brain, I have to figure out how it works somehow on a fundamental level. This means that I get distracted a lot with other projects and ideas and whatnot. It&amp;rsquo;s like constantly trying to dopamine-max, and it&amp;rsquo;s really ass.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>No video for this week</title>
      <link>https://tokisuno.github.io/blog/posts/20250810/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Aug 2025 10:57:45 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tokisuno.github.io/blog/posts/20250810/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;theres-no-video-for-this-week-sorry&#34;&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s no video for this week (sorry!)&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Title. I kept it up for 3 weeks but with family coming, and my medication changing again, I really cannot the time or energy to film and edit anything. As of writing this, I&amp;rsquo;ve already taken a 3-hour nap AFTER sleeping 7 hours last night. Fatigue is sometimes an unfortunate downside of my medication. The video for this week wasn&amp;rsquo;t going to be anything special anyways. I was going to take a song from a small artist, and use it as background music for some sort of aim montage I&amp;rsquo;ve been collecting clips for. But I don&amp;rsquo;t have enough clips anyways LMAO.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Toki Talks - Time commitment into things that matter</title>
      <link>https://tokisuno.github.io/blog/posts/20250804/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 13:19:38 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tokisuno.github.io/blog/posts/20250804/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;welcome-back&#34;&gt;Welcome back!&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Another week, another Toki Talks! This past weekend, I did a lot of reflection on how I have been managing my time, and to say the least I didn&amp;rsquo;t like what I saw in myself.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;commitment-to-content-creation--programming&#34;&gt;Commitment to content creation + programming&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I realized this past weekend that on average, I was only really taking 20 hours per work-week (Monday → Friday) to study programming. This doesn&amp;rsquo;t really add up considering that I don&amp;rsquo;t have a job and spend all day at time. On top of that. My steam records say that I spend approximately 30 hours a week gaming. Therefore, I am spending more time gaming than programming. Why am I spending more time gaming, something that isn&amp;rsquo;t going to bring more value into my life, instead of practicing and perfecting things that will add value?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Toki Talks - Identity and commitment</title>
      <link>https://tokisuno.github.io/blog/posts/20250731/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2025 09:03:47 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tokisuno.github.io/blog/posts/20250731/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;welcome-back&#34;&gt;Welcome back!&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Welcome back to another Toki Talks! These Toki Talks are supposed to be done on Tuesdays, but I quite frankly couldn&amp;rsquo;t think of anything to write about until now, so better sooner than later!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;i-set-very-rigid-concepts-in-my-head-sub-categorization&#34;&gt;I set very rigid &amp;ldquo;concepts&amp;rdquo; in my head (sub-categorization)&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I think a big portion of this problem comes from the fact that I love to separate things and create order of things I cannot understand. It&amp;rsquo;s a problem, and it&amp;rsquo;s a fundamentally flawed way of thinking for multiple reasons, but it&amp;rsquo;s not without its upsides because clearly it has shown some success in my life.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Toki Talks - What to do with streaming...</title>
      <link>https://tokisuno.github.io/blog/posts/20250723/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2025 04:52:05 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tokisuno.github.io/blog/posts/20250723/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Welcome back to another weekly installation of Toki Talks!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve found a routine moreorless that I can stick by and I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing more in terms of programming, but I spend the rest of the day afterwards basically living on autopilot not doing anything at all. I guess this is my wakeup reminder to actually do things that will make me money in the future and dedicate a lot more time towards programming instead of gaming/socializing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Toki Talks - Taking my life back into my own hands</title>
      <link>https://tokisuno.github.io/blog/posts/20250715/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 13:23:02 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tokisuno.github.io/blog/posts/20250715/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;personal-accountability&#34;&gt;Personal accountability&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve done a lot of reflection over the past few days about my life, where I am, and how unhappy I am with it. I&amp;rsquo;ve been slowly digging myself a deeper hole by not taking personal accountability for my own actions and how I handle things. I spend a lot of time on my phone either doom-scrolling or playing Balatro. I spend a lot of time watching YouTube on my phone instead of just being in the moment. I have fallen back onto those vices in order to get me through the day. Then earlier this week, I folded and gave into watching a Dr. K video. This shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be something you fold into, but I have problems accepting reality at times and avoid responsibility for as long as I can. I listened to a video of his on why so many men don&amp;rsquo;t grow up, and I feel like a lot of that video felt like it either directly related to me, or I was getting there. I don&amp;rsquo;t want to get there and I don&amp;rsquo;t want to make things worse for myself. I haven&amp;rsquo;t been studying super hard. I&amp;rsquo;ve honestly been living on autopilot, doing minimal studying and then going off to do aim training. It&amp;rsquo;s good to have hobbies, but your hobbies shouldn&amp;rsquo;t take up most of your time in a given day compared to the work that you have to do. It should be about equal, but the quality of both should be high.For me, it&amp;rsquo;s skewed onto one side and that&amp;rsquo;s the side of leisure, using excuses like my breakup and my illness to take over my head instead of truly reflecting on them and doing what I have to do.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Toki Talks - Rebounding from hardship</title>
      <link>https://tokisuno.github.io/blog/posts/20250710/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 12:29:02 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tokisuno.github.io/blog/posts/20250710/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Well this was supposed to be out earlier this week, but quite frankly I forgot and was really tired from the weekend of gaming I just had.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;goml-forever&#34;&gt;GOML Forever&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;GOML is a yearly Super Smash Brothers Melee tournament I go to, and it&amp;rsquo;s honestly one of my highlights of every year. I love GOML. It has done so much for me. I&amp;rsquo;ve met many cool people going to the tournament, I&amp;rsquo;ve seen many iconic moments in person, and I&amp;rsquo;ve met a lot of the people I&amp;rsquo;ve looked up to. I&amp;rsquo;ve somehow managed to be a small part of a smaller community that I hold so dearly to my heart. For the past two years, I have been volunteering at the event helping run pools (sections of a double elimination bracket) and it&amp;rsquo;s always really fun. I do obviously have moments where I fall behind schedule and sometimes that&amp;rsquo;s just out of my content (infinite floaties being sent to my pool) and honestly that&amp;rsquo;s fine. It&amp;rsquo;s all part of the experience. I love Melee and I love gaming. I love the environment. In person gaming is something you have to experience if you never have before. It&amp;rsquo;s like live sporting but nerdier and depending on the scene, smellier. I am glad to say that the Melee community does a pretty good job with personal hygiene and I did not have a single sweaty-smelling person experience the entire event.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Toki Talks - Happy Canada Day!</title>
      <link>https://tokisuno.github.io/blog/posts/20250701/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 11:25:42 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tokisuno.github.io/blog/posts/20250701/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction--what-is-this&#34;&gt;Introduction :: What is this?&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Every Tuesday is now marked down in my calendar for a weekly blog post to keep the creative writing muscles flowing. I haven&amp;rsquo;t been writing much in all honesty, so this is just one way I can keep at this. I am notoriously bad at keeping a rhythm as of recent, but I have to try and change that for the betterment of my life.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mid-year life update/dump! (2025年)</title>
      <link>https://tokisuno.github.io/blog/posts/20250611/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 11:37:53 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tokisuno.github.io/blog/posts/20250611/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the mid-2025 life update! So far we&amp;rsquo;re through half of the year, and I thought it would be a good idea to write out what&amp;rsquo;s been going on for me so far, what&amp;rsquo;s changed, and what&amp;rsquo;s the relative feeling right now. I will like to preface this post by saying it&amp;rsquo;s not the most uplifting nor is it the most inspiring. I honestly haven&amp;rsquo;t gotten a lot done, especially over the past month since my previous partner broke up with me. I don&amp;rsquo;t want sympathy or any witch-hunting by any means. I know my channel is small enough that this wouldn&amp;rsquo;t happen anyways, but I always want to put it out there incase we have any bad-faith actors. Don&amp;rsquo;t be cringe please.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
