<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Weekly on home</title>
    <link>https://tokisuno.github.io/blog/categories/weekly/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Weekly on home</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-ca</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 13:19:38 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://tokisuno.github.io/blog/categories/weekly/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Toki Talks - Time commitment into things that matter</title>
      <link>https://tokisuno.github.io/blog/posts/20250804/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 13:19:38 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tokisuno.github.io/blog/posts/20250804/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;welcome-back&#34;&gt;Welcome back!&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Another week, another Toki Talks! This past weekend, I did a lot of reflection on how I have been managing my time, and to say the least I didn&amp;rsquo;t like what I saw in myself.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;commitment-to-content-creation--programming&#34;&gt;Commitment to content creation + programming&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I realized this past weekend that on average, I was only really taking 20 hours per work-week (Monday → Friday) to study programming. This doesn&amp;rsquo;t really add up considering that I don&amp;rsquo;t have a job and spend all day at time. On top of that. My steam records say that I spend approximately 30 hours a week gaming. Therefore, I am spending more time gaming than programming. Why am I spending more time gaming, something that isn&amp;rsquo;t going to bring more value into my life, instead of practicing and perfecting things that will add value?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Toki Talks - Identity and commitment</title>
      <link>https://tokisuno.github.io/blog/posts/20250731/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2025 09:03:47 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tokisuno.github.io/blog/posts/20250731/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;welcome-back&#34;&gt;Welcome back!&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Welcome back to another Toki Talks! These Toki Talks are supposed to be done on Tuesdays, but I quite frankly couldn&amp;rsquo;t think of anything to write about until now, so better sooner than later!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;i-set-very-rigid-concepts-in-my-head-sub-categorization&#34;&gt;I set very rigid &amp;ldquo;concepts&amp;rdquo; in my head (sub-categorization)&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I think a big portion of this problem comes from the fact that I love to separate things and create order of things I cannot understand. It&amp;rsquo;s a problem, and it&amp;rsquo;s a fundamentally flawed way of thinking for multiple reasons, but it&amp;rsquo;s not without its upsides because clearly it has shown some success in my life.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Toki Talks - What to do with streaming...</title>
      <link>https://tokisuno.github.io/blog/posts/20250723/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2025 04:52:05 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tokisuno.github.io/blog/posts/20250723/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Welcome back to another weekly installation of Toki Talks!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve found a routine moreorless that I can stick by and I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing more in terms of programming, but I spend the rest of the day afterwards basically living on autopilot not doing anything at all. I guess this is my wakeup reminder to actually do things that will make me money in the future and dedicate a lot more time towards programming instead of gaming/socializing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Toki Talks - Taking my life back into my own hands</title>
      <link>https://tokisuno.github.io/blog/posts/20250715/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 13:23:02 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tokisuno.github.io/blog/posts/20250715/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;personal-accountability&#34;&gt;Personal accountability&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve done a lot of reflection over the past few days about my life, where I am, and how unhappy I am with it. I&amp;rsquo;ve been slowly digging myself a deeper hole by not taking personal accountability for my own actions and how I handle things. I spend a lot of time on my phone either doom-scrolling or playing Balatro. I spend a lot of time watching YouTube on my phone instead of just being in the moment. I have fallen back onto those vices in order to get me through the day. Then earlier this week, I folded and gave into watching a Dr. K video. This shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be something you fold into, but I have problems accepting reality at times and avoid responsibility for as long as I can. I listened to a video of his on why so many men don&amp;rsquo;t grow up, and I feel like a lot of that video felt like it either directly related to me, or I was getting there. I don&amp;rsquo;t want to get there and I don&amp;rsquo;t want to make things worse for myself. I haven&amp;rsquo;t been studying super hard. I&amp;rsquo;ve honestly been living on autopilot, doing minimal studying and then going off to do aim training. It&amp;rsquo;s good to have hobbies, but your hobbies shouldn&amp;rsquo;t take up most of your time in a given day compared to the work that you have to do. It should be about equal, but the quality of both should be high.For me, it&amp;rsquo;s skewed onto one side and that&amp;rsquo;s the side of leisure, using excuses like my breakup and my illness to take over my head instead of truly reflecting on them and doing what I have to do.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Toki Talks - Rebounding from hardship</title>
      <link>https://tokisuno.github.io/blog/posts/20250710/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 12:29:02 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tokisuno.github.io/blog/posts/20250710/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Well this was supposed to be out earlier this week, but quite frankly I forgot and was really tired from the weekend of gaming I just had.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;goml-forever&#34;&gt;GOML Forever&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;GOML is a yearly Super Smash Brothers Melee tournament I go to, and it&amp;rsquo;s honestly one of my highlights of every year. I love GOML. It has done so much for me. I&amp;rsquo;ve met many cool people going to the tournament, I&amp;rsquo;ve seen many iconic moments in person, and I&amp;rsquo;ve met a lot of the people I&amp;rsquo;ve looked up to. I&amp;rsquo;ve somehow managed to be a small part of a smaller community that I hold so dearly to my heart. For the past two years, I have been volunteering at the event helping run pools (sections of a double elimination bracket) and it&amp;rsquo;s always really fun. I do obviously have moments where I fall behind schedule and sometimes that&amp;rsquo;s just out of my content (infinite floaties being sent to my pool) and honestly that&amp;rsquo;s fine. It&amp;rsquo;s all part of the experience. I love Melee and I love gaming. I love the environment. In person gaming is something you have to experience if you never have before. It&amp;rsquo;s like live sporting but nerdier and depending on the scene, smellier. I am glad to say that the Melee community does a pretty good job with personal hygiene and I did not have a single sweaty-smelling person experience the entire event.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Toki Talks - Happy Canada Day!</title>
      <link>https://tokisuno.github.io/blog/posts/20250701/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 11:25:42 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tokisuno.github.io/blog/posts/20250701/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction--what-is-this&#34;&gt;Introduction :: What is this?&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Every Tuesday is now marked down in my calendar for a weekly blog post to keep the creative writing muscles flowing. I haven&amp;rsquo;t been writing much in all honesty, so this is just one way I can keep at this. I am notoriously bad at keeping a rhythm as of recent, but I have to try and change that for the betterment of my life.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
