<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Esperanto on home</title>
    <link>https://tokisuno.github.io/blog/tags/esperanto/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Esperanto on home</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-ca</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2025 08:46:12 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://tokisuno.github.io/blog/tags/esperanto/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>My short experince with learning Esperanto</title>
      <link>https://tokisuno.github.io/blog/posts/20250407/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2025 08:46:12 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tokisuno.github.io/blog/posts/20250407/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;format&#34;&gt;Format&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The first section is in Esperanto talking about whatever I want to talk about in Esperanto.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;However, the second portion is about my learning of Esperanto.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;esperanto-saluton&#34;&gt;Esperanto Saluton!&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ankoraŭ mi lernas Espernato ĉiutage! Ĉiutaga ekzercoj estas tre utilaj. Mi ne skribas kun la akuzitivo tre bone ĉar mi lernis ĝin lastatempe.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mi uzas Duolingo kaj Anki por lerni kaj praktiki.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-struggles&#34;&gt;The struggles&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t speak a language that has a consistent case system like Esperanto, so it&amp;rsquo;s weird to get used to. I just started learning how the case works so I don&amp;rsquo;t have much practice with it, but I am practising nonetheless.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 Weeks of Esperanto</title>
      <link>https://tokisuno.github.io/blog/posts/20250327/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2025 12:16:47 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tokisuno.github.io/blog/posts/20250327/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;sinprezento&#34;&gt;Sinprezento&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Saluton! Mi estas tokisuno. Mi ĝojas rekonti vin. Mi estas Kanadano. Dum 2 semanjnoj, mi lernas Esperanton.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;going-back-to-my-roots&#34;&gt;Going back to my roots&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t know if many people realize this or have this in their mind when they think of me, but I am a Linguist. I mean, in reality we all are Linguists, but I studied Linguistics at University for just over 4 years of my life. I generally have a passion for learning, but I really (really) love learning about culture and language. I am planning on learning toki pona with my partner once she&amp;rsquo;s finished with her term, but I have the itch to learn another conlang for the time being. So with that, I am going to study Esperanto daily for the next 11/12 days.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
